Neil Girardi

Developer, Web & Mobile http://neilgirardi.com

Overview

Experienced and passionate developer skilled in front-end and back-end web and android technologies.

Front-End Skills

Ajax UI development, JavaScript, jQuery, jQuery UI, Pixel-perfect CSS, Clean semantic HTML, Speed / Performance Optimization, Mobile web development, Amazon Web Services: (CloudFront / S3), Apache HTTPD, Web typography (Cufon, @FontFace, Google Fonts), Prototype, Scriptaculous.

Back-End Skills

Object-Oriented PHP 5, Android, Java, MySQL relational databases, JSON, XML, CodeIgniter, WordPress. Agile, Ant, Git, Ivy, JUnit, MVC, Robojuice, Subversion, Test Driven Development (TDD), UNIX / Linux – BASH.

Employment

Developer, GrubHub

April 2011 - August 2012

- Created three new Android apps and scaled up a fourth app over a nine-month period.
- Learned Android SDK and developed a publicly available app from scratch in four months.
- Responsible for implementing all front-end / UI components of Android apps.
- Worked on both the front-end and back-end of Allmenus.com, a PHP 5 / MSSQL website built with Codelgniter and jQuery.
- Reduced the page-load times for Allmenus.com by a factor of 4, resulting in higher searchengine rankings.
- Completely rebuilt the user interface of Allmenus.com using Ajax, jQuery, PHP 5, CSS, and HTML resulting in higher conversions of online orders.

Implementation Engineer, Group Commerce

January 2011 - April 2011

- Front-end developer for white-label group buying sites built on a .NET / MySQL / Windows / IIS stack.
- Implemented the user interface for Group Commerce's CMS using Ajax, jQuery, and CSS.
- Liaised with clients for pre-production technical meetings, as well as development and production issues.
- Clients included Parents Magazine, Thrillist, and Active Media.

Web Developer, Millennium Promise

June 2010 - December 2011

- · Built a custom CMS from scratch using PHP 5, MySQL, jQuery, CSS, and HTML.
- Managed daily content updates to the public-facing website.
- Drafted and executed HTML emails for fund-raising campaigns.

Freelance Web Developer April 2008 - June 2010

- Clients included:
 - L'Oreal Implemented new UI features for a corporate-facing video library app using iQuery and CSS.
 - Mills Real Estate & Auction Built a custom CMS from scratch using PHP 5 and MySQL, jQuery, CSS, and HTML.
 - Celsius Built a recording artist's official website using PHP 5, MySQL, jQuery, CSS and HTML. Website features include JavaScript animation, a custom MP3 player, and a back-end solution for email campaigns.

Account Manager, PostWorks

August 1999 - January 2008

- Sales executive and project manager for post-production services used by TV and film projects.
- Supervised technical services provided for projects such as "The Bourne Ultimatum."

Systems Engineer, **Digital Editing Solutions**

January 1999 - August 1999

• Responsible for designing, building and supporting custom mobile digital post-production systems for television and film productions.

Education:

New York University – SCPS 2011 Java Programming

School of Visual Arts – Continuing Education 2009 JavaScript Programming 2008 PHP Programming with MySQL

2008 CSS

Syracuse University – SI Newhouse School of Public Communications

1996 Bachelor of Science: Electronic Media Production

1992 Maxwell Citizenship Conference Scholarship